Emily B. Siegel

Data Scientist and Geoscientist with 9+ years of achieving actionable insights with diverse datasets. Passion for problem-solving and a reputation for mastering new roles and technologies, as well as communicating complex information to nontechnical audiences.

<u>LinkedIn</u>
<u>GitHub</u>

Data Science Portfolio

PROJECTS

- Starbucks Customer Segmentation using K-Means Clustering
- Breast Cancer Detection in Mammograms using Convolutional Neural Networks
- Classifying Passive vs. Active Revenge in Related Subreddits using NLP
- Predicting Ames, Iowa Real Estate Prices with Linear Regression

EXPERIENCE

S&P Global Ratings, Centennial, CO — Data Scientist

NOV 2021 - PRESENT

Develop Python automation solutions incl. ML models that maximize data capabilities for stakeholders throughout the whole project lifecycle, from design and development through testing and deployment.

Well Data Labs, Denver, CO — *Data Research Analyst & Support Analyst* FEB 2019 - MAY 2021

- Applied best practices in statistical analysis to drive business value.
- Validated, tested, and monitored the performance of machine learning models. Standardized accuracy metrics and optimized testing workflow.
- Automated high-frequency time series data wrangling and analyses using Excel VBA and Python. Integrated Python scripts in custom built dashboards.
- Coauthored a peer-reviewed paper, client case studies, and blog posts that address key market needs while proposing data-driven solutions and strategies.
- Tracked product usage, deployed customer retention initiatives, and developed technical documentation with every new release.

Reliance OFS (formerly FMC Technologies), Denver, $CO-Log\ Data\ Analyst$

AUG 2015 - FEB 2019

- Due to newly acquired technology and previous pulsed neutron expertise, I implemented a new data service, increasing revenue and bringing in 3 new clients.
- Assessed wellbore integrity and identified potential casing and cement issues to maximize the efficiency of field operations while ensuring safety.
- Trained 2 new analysts on all department functions and created instructional documentation including technical manuals, reference materials, and workflows.

Baker Hughes, Denver, CO — Geoscientist / Team Lead

APRIL 2013 - AUG 2015

- Led the Cased Hole Petrophysics team of 5 people within the Reservoir Development group. Resulted in 600+ successfully delivered projects yearly.
- Processed and analyzed data using various petrophysical techniques and technologies to provide and present solutions to clients.
- Vital internal role mentoring and teaching data processing techniques, expanding the company's Cased Hole business internationally to South American markets.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Data Science Immersive
JUNE 2021- SEPT 2021

University of Vermont

B.S. Geology, Minor Studio Art AUG 2008 - MAY 2012

SKILLS

Core Competencies:

Analytics + Research
Machine Learning
Cognitive Automation
Project Management
Technical Writing
Presenting
Lean-Agile

Software:

PyCharm | Jupyter |
Databricks | Alteryx | Data
visualization (Spotfire &
PowerBI) | CRM (Salesforce)
| Version control (GitHub,
Azure DevOps & BitBucket) |
Software product planning
(Pivotal Tracker) | Product
UX (Pendo) | Adobe Creative

LANGUAGES

Python | SQL | Excel VBA | Bash | Hebrew | French

PUBLICATIONS

SPE 204145 (2021)
Employing a Suite of
Machine-Learning
Algorithms in a Holistic
Approach to Trouble-Stage
Recognition and Failure
Diagnostics